The Yale School of Music Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Yale School of Music Papers
1875-1993
MSS 3
Yale University Music Library
14.7
(35 boxes)
The Yale School of Music Papers include correspondence, student works, lists of students, concert programs, and miscellaneous items.
Yale School of Music
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Arrangement
In 5 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Student Compositions and Papers. III. Programs. IV. Bulletins. V. Student registers.
Scope and Contents
The Yale School of Music Papers document the School and its activities with correspondence, student works, concert programs, and miscellaneous items. The correspondence includes letters to and from Yale administrators, faculty members, composers, performing musicians, and benefactors; it is limited to 1897-1918 and 1943-1950. Horatio Parker, who served as Dean from 1904 to 1919, is especially well represented. The concert programs feature performances by Yale faculty and students, and also include some New Haven concerts by performers not affiliated with Yale. Dates of the programs range from 1875 to 1993, but it is important to note that programs were not systematically collected during all periods.
Biographical / Historical
In 1855, the Yale Corporation appointed Gustave Stoeckel to supervise the College's musical activities; his duties would eventually include directing music in the Yale chapel and teaching non-credit courses. A "Musical Department" was established in 1890 to provide formal academic instruction in music; Stoeckel became its first professor. In 1894, four students received Yale's first Bachelor of Music degrees, and Horatio Parker and Samuel Sanford were appointed to the faculty. That date is traditionally regarded as the founding of the Yale School of Music, although the School's name did not become official until 1914. Parker became the first Dean in 1904, a post he held until his death in 1919. He was succeeded as Dean by David Stanley Smith (1920-1940), Richard Donovan (acting, 1940-1941), Bruce Simonds (1941-1954), Luther Noss (1954-1970), Philip Nelson (1970-1980), Frank Tirro (1980-1989), Ezra Laderman (1989-1995), and Robert Blocker (1995-present). Though it initially concentrated on undergraduate education, the School of Music began offering graduate degrees in 1932, and discontinued the Bachelor of Music degree in 1958. Undergraduate instruction was henceforth provided by a separate Department of Music, established in 1940, which also offered graduate degrees in the history and theory of music.
Further information about the history of the Yale School of Music may be found in Luther Noss, A History of the Yale School of Music, 1855-1970 (New Haven, Yale School of Music, 1984). Scholars interested in the School's history may also wish to examine the Gilmore Library's archival collections relating to individuals who taught or studied at Yale, including Horatio Parker, Charles Ives, David Stanley Smith, Richard Donovan, Marshall Bartholomew, Quincy Porter, Paul Hindemith, David Kraehenbuehl, and Mel Powell.
Composers -- Correspondence; Conservatories of music -- United States; Music teachers -- Correspondence; Music -- Instruction and study -- United States; Bispham, David, 1857-1921; Burton, Frederick R. (Frederick Russell), 1861-1909; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953; Erb, J. Lawrence (John Lawrence), 1877-1950; Ginastera, Alberto, 1916-1983; Guilmant, Alexandre, 1837-1911; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Haesche, William E. (William Edwin), 1867-1929; Harling, W. Franke (William Franke), 1887-1958; Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955; Jepson, Harry Benjamin, 1870-1952; Kelley, Edgar Stillman, 1857-1944; Leginska, Ethel, 1886-1970; Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1873-1953; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; Parker, Horatio W. (Horatio William), 1863-1919; Rogers, Francis, 1870-1951; Sanford, Samuel, 1849-1910; Schirmer, Gustave, 1890-1965; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951; Simonds, Bruce; Skinner, Ernest M.; Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949; Spalding, Albert, 1888-1953; Steinert, Morris, 1831-1912; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971; Sundelius, Marie, 1884-1958; Troostwyk, Isidore; Walton, William, 1902-1983; Yale School of Music
- Correspondence, Series I
  General
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Sears, J.M., 1897 Jan 18; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hadley, Arthur, 1901; 3 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Haesche, William Edwin, 1901; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kelley, E.S. (dictated), 1901; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sanford, Samuel, 1901 Sep 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps Jr., 1901 Jul 12; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hadley, Arthur, 1902; 5 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Haesche, William Edwin, 1902; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jepson, Henry, 1902; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1902, typed examination text (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - concerning Horatio Parker's leave of absence, 1902; typed page (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kelley, Edges Stillman (dictated), 1902; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Marsh, Egbert, 1902 Apr 8; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sanford, Samuel, 1902 Mar 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps Jr., 1902 Apr 12; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tyler(?), 1902 Dec 12; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - about Haesche's symphony in A flat, 1902; newspaper clipping (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Burton, Frederick R., 1903 Jan 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hadley, Arthur, 1903 Mar l4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hadley, Arthur, 1903 Jun 8; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kelley, Edgar Stillman, 1903 Mar 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Tyler(?), 1903 May 11; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vaill, J.H., 1903 Jun 5; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vaill, J.H., 1903 Jun 8; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1904; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Contract between Horatio Parker and Alexandre Guilmand, 1904; typed and signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1905 Nov 20; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - estimate of receipts and expenses of the Department of Music, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cunningham, Claude, 1906 Nov 16; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hagan, M.E., 1906 Jan 9; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hardy, Caroline, 1906 Nov 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - McClung, Lee, 1906; 2 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - McClung, Lee, 1906; 4 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Metzger, H.S., 1906 Nov 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Owen, Ina, 1906 Dec 17; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1906; 2 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Robertson, William Hall, 1906 Jul 6; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Steinert, Morris, 1906 Oct 5; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr., 1906 Nov 6; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Urchs, Ernest, manager of Lhévinne, 1906 Oct; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Wolfsohn, Henry, 1906 Dec 21; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Music students, 1906; 12 typed lists (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anracher, Harry R., 1907 Apr 9; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Benton, Alfred, 1907 Jan 29; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Breazeale, H.R., 1907 Mar 6; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Buselmaier, K., 1907 Apr 17; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clare, H.N., 1907 Jan 29; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ellis, G.A., 1907 Dec 2; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fowler, Marion W., 1907 May 6; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jotten, Luella, 1907 Mar 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - McClung, Lee, 1907 Dec 9; 3 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - McGregor, D.A., 1907 May 27; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1907; 9 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Porter, William S., 1907; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Salmons, M.C., 1907 Apr 29; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Schirmer, G., 1907 May 21; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Seiter, Joseph C., 1907 Dec 10; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr., 1907; 3 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - United States Marine Band, 1907; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wallett, Alice M., 1907; card (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wier, M.C., 1907 Nov 11; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - William, Evan, 1907 Feb 23; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Music students, 1907; 17 typed lists (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Receipts and expenditures, 1907; typed list (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Books and scores for YSM, 1907; typed list (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agramonte, Emilio, 1908 Oct 10; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Albert, C.J., 1908 Feb 15; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dutscher, George M., 1908 Apr 22; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Eaton, Edward D., 1908 Sep 22; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Francis, S.M., 1908 May 26; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Granville, W.A., 1908 Oct 16; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gardner, Frances, 1908 Mar 12; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gibbs, Ohas, 1908 Apr 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Guelich, Harry D., 1908 Apr 15; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Joseph, Israel, 19O8 Oct 12; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Locke, Arthur W., 1908 Sep 28; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1908; 9 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ross, Frank A., 1908 Mar 24; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Salt, Thomas W., 1908 Sep 16; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Schirmer, G., 1908; 2 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Schuckai, H., 1908 Nov 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Schutz, Leo, 1908; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Skinner, E.B, 1908 Sep 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Spinnay, A.W., 1908 Sep 23; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps Jr., 1908 Sep 19; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Thompson, Everara, 1908 Jan 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Wier, M.C., 1908 May 6; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Music students, 1908; 20 typed lists (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bing, Florence E., 1909 Nov 15; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bispham, David, 1909; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Black, E.N., 1909 Mar 20; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Charlton, London, 1909 Jun 11; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cole, 1909; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dickinson, George R., 1909; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Greenleaf, Margaret, 1909; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hadley, Arthur, 1909 Nov 3; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hare, Lulu F., 1909 Oct 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Morse, Clifford, 1909 Feb 8; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1909; 5 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Philharmonic Society of N.Y., 1909; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Schirmer, G., 1909; 6 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Brainard A., 1909 Oct 19; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Smith, David Stanley, 1909 Dec 23; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanby, Louise E., 1909 Oct 19; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - West, George Alexander, 1909 Jan 21; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Music students, 1909; 20 typed lists (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - unidentified item, 1909; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Barnes, (?), 1910 Feb 11; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cutter, Ephraim, M.D., 1910; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cutter, Ephraim: "Of interest to those who desire to sing", printed booklet (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - List of titles offered to the 1910 meeting of the Massachusetts Medical Society (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Felsburg, Louis, 1910 Dec 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Jones, Edith Daniel, 1910 May 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1910; 6 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Parker's secretary, 1910; 3 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Porter, William S., 1910 Oct 17; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Speier, Edna, 1910 Nov 21; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps Jr., 1910; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Vito, Perrt di, 1910 Sep 27; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Music students, 1910; 13 typed lists (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Black, Edwin M., 1911 Feb 11; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Day, George Parmly, 1911 Jan 30; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Durham, Henry, 1911 May 10; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1911; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Scranton, Clara Minerva, 1911 Nov 12; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Troostwyk, Isidore, 1911 Jan 1; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Heils, R.J., 1912 Jun 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Harling, Frank, 1913 Oct 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Leginska, Ethel, 1913 Dec 25; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Parker, Anne (Mrs. Horatio Parker) 1913 Aug 21, autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1913 Sep 25; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1913 Oct 22; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Parker's secretary, 1913; 6 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rogers, Francis, 1913 Dec 10; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sanford, E.Z., 1913 Nov 14; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sanford, James Nelson, 1913 Nov; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Troostwyk, Isidore, 1913 Jun; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    (see Parker)
  - Johnson, Frederic B., 1914 Sep 2; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Leginska, Ethel, 1914; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1911 Apr 8; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Parker's secretary, 1914; 16 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Smith, David Stanley, 1914; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Rogers, Francis, 1914 Jan 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - unidentified item, 1914 Feb 25; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cutter, Ephraim, 1915 Sep 23; card (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Day, George Parmly, 1915 May 20; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fields, Curtis P., 1915 Sep 23; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hadley, Arthur, 1915 Sep 24; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lane, Elizabeth, 1915 Oct 1; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Parker's secretary (Smith, D.S.), 1915; 21 typed letters, 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Rogers, Francis, 1915 Dec 26; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - unidentified item, 1915 May 24; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Adams, A.F., 1916 Dec 27; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
    (music manager)
  - Atwater, Wm. Charmley, 1916 Oct 15; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Charlton, Loudon, 1916 Dec 30; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Denison, W.A., 1916 Jun 9; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Erb, J. Lawrence, 1916 Oct; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hackney, Arthur C., 1916; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Heill, R.T., 1916 Jun 19; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hughes, Royal D., 1916 Oct 16; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Johnson, Frederic B., 1916 Nov 25; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Keogh, Andrew, 1916 Feb 19; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Meiler, Geo. A., 1916 Jun 17; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Miessner, W. Otto, 1916 Dec 9; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1916 Dec 11; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1916; 3 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Parker's secretary, 1916; 29 typed letters, 3 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Smith, F. Lorenz, 1916 Oct 21; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - McSweeney, D.F., manager, 1916 Apr 5; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Warren, Jeanne (Mrs. Samuel Warren) 1916 Feb 16, autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Wessels, Frederic J., manager, 1916 Mar 15; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Whitney, C.E., 1916 Oct 24; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - unidentified items, 1916; 2 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Avary, F.C., 1917 Jan 24; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brown, Geo. E., 1917 Jan 31; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Charlton, Loudon, manager, 1917; 3 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chatfield, R.M., 1917; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1917 Mar 26; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1917 Apr 3; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Day, George Parmly, 1917; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hilliard, Elma E., 1917 Feb 4; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hotchkiss, (?), 1917 Jan 9; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Johnson, Frederic B., 1917; 7 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Jones, Frederic S. (Dean Yale College), 1917; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lewis, Marguerite S., 1917 Jun 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mason, Wallace E., 1917 Jan 10; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - O'Shea, Bernhard, 1917 Feb 16; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - O'Shea, Bernard, 1917 May 1; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1917 Jun 25; 20 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Parker, Horatio to Stanley Knight, 1917 Jun 25; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Parker's secretary, 1917; 31 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Reidy, Anna E., 1917 Jan 6; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Rhodes, Jeremiah, 1917 Jan 25; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Rogers, Francis, 1917 Feb 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Slawson, S.J., 1917 Jan 16; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Spalding, Albert, 1917 Feb 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps Jr., 1917 Mar 27; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps Jr., 1917 Apr 17; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Sundelius, Marie, 1917 Feb 1; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Troostwyk, Leo, 1917 Jan 17; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - unidentified items, 1917; 2 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Peddlers(?), 1918 Mar 5; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Milhaud, Darius to Bruce Simonds, 1943; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Simonds, Bruce, 1943; 5 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Stravinsky, Igor to Bruce Simonds, 1943; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Simonds, Bruce to Leopold Stokowski, 1945 Dec 20; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Stokowski, Leopold to Bruce Simonds, 1945 Dec 20; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1946 Nov 20; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Simonds, Bruce, 1946 Nov 21; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ginastera, Alberto, 1947 Jan 24; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ginastera, Alberto, 1947 Jan 29; telegram (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Simonds, Bruce, 1947 Jan 28; telegram (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Wagner, M. Antoinette, 1948; card (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Dowling, Lyle, 1949; 3 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Furnir, E.S., 1949; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Honegger, Arthur to Bruce Simonds, 1949 Jul 30; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold to Bruce Simonds, 1949 May 31; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Simonds, Bruce, 1949; 4 typed letters (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Simond's secretary, 1949; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Walton, William to Bruce Simonds, 1949 Jul 6; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Note about address of William Walton, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1950; 4 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Simonds, Bruce, 1950 Sep 18; typed letter (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - King, Francus Strang, undated; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Parker, Horatio, undated; autograph letter (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Pierce, C.B., undated; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Porter, W. Steorus, undated; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Proctor, George, undated; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Sanders, Frank K., undated; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Walbridge, Charles Carter, undated; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Student Compositions and Papers, Series II
  - Student Compositions, arranged by year
    - Pre-1900 - 1911/12 (Box 1)
    - 1912-1916 (Box 2)
    - 1916/17-1920/21 (Box 3)
    - 1921-1923 (Box 4)
    - 1923/24-1925/26 (Box 5)
    - 1925/26-1927/28 (Box 6)
    - 1927/28-1931 (Box 7)
    - 1930/31-1933 (Box 8)
    - 1933/34-1939 (Box 9)
    - 1939/40-1942 (Box 10)
    - Term papers, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Compositions, arranged by name of composer
    - Adams - Bracher (Box 11)
    - Brown - Dyer (Box 12)
    - Edwards - Jensen (Box 13)
    - Johns - Moog (Box 14)
    - Moog - Rubano (Box 15)
    - Rudas - Tinsley (Box 16)
    - Tinsley - Zito (Box 17)
    - Written Theses, Mus. B., 1921 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
- Programs, Series III
  - undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1875-1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1898-1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1909 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jan 1910-Oct 1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nov 1910-Aug 1911 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sep 1911-1913 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1921-Aug 1922 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sept 1922-Aug 1923 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Sept 1923-Jan 1924 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Feb 1924-Dec 1924 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1925 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1926 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Jan 1927-Feb 1927 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mar 1927-Dec 1927 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1928 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1929 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 1930 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1931 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 1932 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 1933 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - 1936 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 1937 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 1938 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 1939 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 1941 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - 1942 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - 1945 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - 1946 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - 1947 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - 1948 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Jan 1949-Aug 1949 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Sept 1949-Mar 1950 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Apr 1950-Dec 1950 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Jan 1951-May 1951 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - June 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Jan 1952-Mar 1952 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Apr 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Jan 1953-May 1953 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - June 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Jan 1954-May 1954 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - June 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 9, Folder 50)